穴ぐらから出てきたモンが鬼だってってことにならねぇようにしなよ？
You better hope the beast that comes out
of the cave isn't a monster.
なぁあにき  腹減ってねぇか？
Hey, are you hungry?
今はメシどころじゃねぇか…
Guess he has other things to worry about.
そういやぁあにきって笑ったことねぇよな
Say, you've never laughed before,
have you?
一生むっつり顔のままになっちまっても知らねぇんだから
Fine, be that way your whole life
for all I care.
もう女房のとこにゃ帰らねぇ
I'm never going back to my wife.
お前とずっと一緒にいてぇよぉ！
I want to stay with you forever.
そうだね
Me too.
こ…こんな山ん中で何してやがんだ！
Get a room!
熊にでも食われちまえ！こんにゃろこんにゃろこんにゃろー！
Get eaten by a bear! Take this, and this!
った…
Ow.
なんだ!?
What the...
おい…大丈夫か
Hey, you all right?
こいつ…ふざけんのもいい加減にしろよ！
What the heck? Has he lost his mind?
あにき！
Hyakkimaru!
出てきやがれー！
Come on out!
こんちくしょう…
Dang it.
逃げられちまったなぁ
It got away.
あっ あにき 村があるぞ
Hey look, there's a village.
仕方ない…あそこで力を…
I guess
I'll have to regain my energy there.
Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
But I still wanna dance
眠れないくらい
I can't even sleep
情熱の火はいつしか　いつの日にか
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
はなから気付いている
From the beginning I knew
炎はいつか消える
One day the flames would die out
何も要らないはずだった
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
なのにまだ I'm so serious
But even now, I'm so serious
ああ　まだ間に合う
Ah... I still have time to make it
ああ ただ Burn it up Baby
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it's not that bad either
ああ Give me fire!
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
ああただBurn it up
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#7 The story of the Jorogumo silk spider
もう身体を引き上げることもできないなんて…
How wretched I am,
I can't even pull myself up.
なんかめんどくせぇ村だなぁ…
What a bothersome village.
"TRAVELER'S PASS"
村を守るために見張りを強めてるんでなぁ
We have guards out
to protect the village now.
守るって？何からさ
Protect from what?
最近、村に人さらいが出るのさ
-There's been a kidnapper around here.
-A kidnapper?
人さらい！
あぁ 夜な夜な村の人間がいなくなっちまう
Yeah, our villagers keep disappearing
almost nightly.
あの見張り台だって、そのために置いたんだ
That's what those watchtowers are for.
お前も怪しいやつを見つけたら、すぐに知らせてくれ
You let us know
if you see anything suspicious.
なぁ、あにき
Hey.
人が消えるってのはおいら絶対 あのクモのバケモンのせいだと思んだ
I bet it's that spider monster
kidnapping the villagers.
この村にとっちゃあおおごとみてぇだし
Seems like a big problem for them.
おいらたちで何とかすれば人助けんなるし
We could help this village out.
褒美もかなーり貰えるはずだぜ！
I bet there'd be a good reward, too.
これだけは、完成させないと…
This, I must complete.
おい！あんた！しっかりしろ！
Hey, you! Are you okay?
すまん！驚かすつもりはなかった！
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
おい…どこか悪いのか？
Are you sick?
死にそうな顔だ…とりあえずうちに来な！
You're as pale as death. Come to my house.
食いモンくらい出してやれる  歩けるか？
I can give you something to eat.
Can you walk?
歩ける…
Yes, I can...
よし、ついてきな
Okay, come with me.
まずはこいつの精気をいただくか…
I'll suck out his life force first.
そういやぁあんた、名前は？俺は弥二郎ってんだ
Say, what's your name? I'm Yajiro.
そんなものはない
I have none.
ない？ ない か
You don't? Well then.
よし
There.
じゃあ、おはぎってのはどうだ
Then how about Ohagi?
おはぎ
-Ohagi?
-You were lying in a bed of hagi flowers.
萩の花ん中で寝てたろ
何とでも呼べ
Have it your way.
お  それじゃあおはぎ！腹減ってんだろ
Okay then, Ohagi. You must be hungry.
食いな
Eat up.
何だいこれは…まずそうだねぇ
What's this? Looks nasty.
遠慮すんな
Go ahead, eat up.
うまい！
It's good.
おはぎ！お前どっから来た？ もしよかったら教えてくれ
Ohagi, if it's okay,
tell me where you came from.
よくないから教えないよ
It's not, so I won't.
な…ならなんであんなところで寝てたんだ？
Then why were you lying there?
好きで寝てたわけないだろう
As if I had a choice.
ったく力さえ戻りゃ、さっさとこんなところ出て行きたいよ
If I had the strength,
I'd leave this place this very second.
お前は食べないのかい？
Aren't you going to eat?
あ…あぁ
Huh? Oh...
俺はさっき食べたばっかりだからな
I just ate before you came.
何の音だ
What's that noise?
いいから早く食え！
Don't mind it, eat up.
俺は仕事に行かなきゃならん 夕暮れまでには戻る 食ったら寝ててくれ
I have to go to work. I'll be back
by dusk. Eat up and go to sleep.
妙な人間だねぇ
What a strange human.
あたいのモンに手ぇ出すんじゃないよ
It's mine. Don't touch it.
田畑に作物なんもねぇ
No rice paddies, no fields.
あにき、この村食いモンは難しいかもなぁ
We might not find any food
in this village.
なんだなんだ？
What's going on?
なぁ、あんた  あれ何て書いてあるんだ？
Hey, what's that sign say?
あぁ、人さらいを捕まえたら褒美をくれるとさ
It says there's a reward
for finding the kidnapper.
まぁ、何度同じことをしても 一向に捕まる気配はねぇが
Not that it's helping any
in finding the kidnapper.
ほらな。おいらの思ったとおり
See, told you so.
こりゃ褒美はいただきだな！
That reward is ours then!
なんだ坊主  心当たりがあるのか？
What, you know who it might be?
あんたも褒美目当てかい？ でも首突っ込まないほうがいいぜ？
After the reward too?
I'd stay out of it if I were you.
なんせ相手はバケモンなんだから
We're dealing with a monster here.
バケモン！？
A monster?
静まれ、静まれぇーっ！ 手を止めてはならん！ 作業を続けろー！
Quiet, quiet! Don't stop, keep working!
バケモンが出るなら 日が暮れたこれからだろうせ、あにき
I bet the monster only comes out
once it gets really dark.
昼間やみくもに探し回る体力もねぇし
We don't have the energy
to search during the day.
要領よくやんねぇと…
Gotta be smart.
さ、行こうぜあにき
Right, let's go.
人間の食いモンじゃ、やはりこの程度か…
I guess this is the most I can do
on human food.
すまん、すっかり暗くなっちまった
Sorry, I got off work late.
ずっと起きてたのか？
You stayed up?
寝てたよ  でも外が騒がしかったから目が覚めた
I slept. But I woke up
because of all the noise outside.
あぁ  山の仕事場でまた人死にが出た
Yeah, another man died
out at work in the mountains.
炎天下の重労働だ  無理もない
It's hard work out in the hot sun.
It's harsh.
なんでそこまでするんだい？ 死んだら元も子もないだろう
Why do you work so hard?
Is it worth dying for?
この村は砕石で成り立ってるんだ
This is a quarry village.
上がりが減ることを領主は許さない
Our lord won't allow us to slow down.
人間てのは不自由なモンだねぇ
Humans have no freedom.
顔色が悪いな！
You look dreadful.
メシは食えてるようだが…
I see you've eaten, but...
ゴキカブリだ！
A cockroach.
なぜ逃がすんだい？
Why did you let it go?
人間が死ぬのはよくて 虫けらが死ぬのはイヤなのかい？
It's okay for humans to die, but not bugs?
人も虫も同じだ 生きていることに変わりはねぇ
Humans and bugs, they're all the same.
Life is life.
そんなことを言う人間に初めて会ったよ
I've never met a human
who speaks like that before.
あんた変わってるね
You're strange.
そうか？そんなことよりまずは食え！
Am I? Anyways, eat up.
そして寝ろ  人間、それが一番だ
And sleep. That solves everything.
あんたみたいな男、初めてだよ
You're not like any man I've met before.
空腹はお互い様だね
I guess we both are hungry.
はぁ、疲れたぁ
Ugh, I'm pooped out.
ひと晩じゅう歩いて収穫なしかよ！
We walked all night for nothing.
どこに隠れてんだ？あのクモのバケモン…
Where's that spider monster hiding?
もう頭も回らねぇ  涼しいうちに少し寝とこうぜ、あにき
My brain isn't working anymore.
Let's sleep while it's still cool.
なぁなぁ  あれ何て書いてあんだ？
Hey, what's that say?
昨日の晩にまた人が消えて、褒美が多くなるとある
Another man disappeared last night,
so the reward went up.
昨日！バケモンの気配もなかったのに
Last night? But there weren't
any signs of monsters.
おいらの見込み違いで人さらいは… バケモンの仕業じゃない？
Maybe I was wrong.
Maybe it's not a monster...
ねぇ、人さらいの人捕まっちゃうの？
Hey, will the man who takes people away
get caught?
そったらことにはならへん
Don't worry, he won't get caught.
どげに褒美を積まれても、領主に寝返る男なんぞ この村にはただの1人もおりゃせん
No man of this village would
snitch to the lord no matter the reward.
この村じゃ、 もう虫か雑草ぐらいしか腹に入れるものがねぇ
We have nothing else to eat here
but bugs and weeds.
ドクダミかじって夜まで木陰で横になろう
Guess we'll chew on herbs
and rest till night.
おはぎ… お前さらにやつれてるな こいつは…
Ohagi, you're growing weaker and weaker.
Are you...
あんた…今朝はやけに早く出かけたね
You left mighty early this morning.
まだ外は暗いのに灯りも持たず
It was still dark,
but you didn't even take a torch.
山での仕事以外にも何かやってんのかい？
Do you have another job
besides the quarry?
月の沈む時刻にひと仕事あってな
Yeah, a bit of a job as the moon sets.
そっちが本業みたいなもんだ
It's actually my main job.
大変だねぇ
Must be tough.
おはぎ、俺の見たところお前はなんかしらの病だ
Ohagi, as far as I can tell,
you're sick with something.
だがこの村には医者がいねぇ
But this village has no doctors.
旅の札がないお前が村を出るのは難しいだろうが…
You can't leave this village
without a traveler's pass.
俺なら、確実に逃してやれる
But I can get you out of here.
まぁこの村じゃ若いエサにはありつけそうもない
Well, seems like I won't find
any young prey here.
とっととおさらばしたいのは山々だけど…
I would leave this place if I could.
私に払えるもんなどないよ
But I have nothing to pay you with.
生きていてくれればいい
I just want you to live.
そうだったね…
Yes, that's right.
私はゴキカブリと同じってわけだ
I'm the same as a cockroach.
あぁ、同じだ  命の重さに変わりはねぇ
Yes, you are.
All lives matter just the same.
私だって死ぬ気はないからね
I don't wish to die, either.
頼むとするよ
Help me, then.
引き受けた! 1日でも早いほうがいいな
Gladly. We should go as soon as possible.
今夜、月が沈み夜が明ける前にやる
Tonight, after the moon sets
and before dawn breaks.
それまでに休んでおいてくれ
Rest until then.
人さらいがバケモンじゃなかったら おいらたちじゃ見つけることすら難しいなぁ
If the kidnapper isn't a monster,
we won't be able to find him.
何にしろ今夜が山！
Anyways, tonight's our last chance.
あにき、この村でのバケモン探し最後の夜だ
This will be our last night
looking for the monster here.
腹に力は入らねぇけど、気合い入れていこうぜ！
We might be hungry, but let's do it.
どこへ行くんだい？ そっちは村の出口じゃないだろ？
Where are we going?
The village exit isn't this way.
あっちは柵と見張りで出られねぇ 抜け道はこっちだ！
There are guards over there.
The secret passage is this way.
空が白んでくるまでの一刻でそこまで行く
We'll get there right before dawn.
辛いだろうが耐えてくれ
You'll have to bear with me.
空きっ腹でふた晩歩きづめは子供には堪える～
It's tough on a kid to walk two nights
on an empty stomach.
あにき、すまねぇ  今回は空振りみてぇだ
Sorry Hyakkimaru,
guess we lucked out this time.
諦めて次の村へ…え？
We should give up and go...
おはぎ  辛ければ少し休むか？
Ohagi, do you need to rest a little?
バカにするな  お前の精気を吸ってもいいんだぞ
Who do you think I am?
I could suck the life out of you.
昨日ここで会ったおっちゃん…？
You're the guy we met yesterday.
褒美目当ての坊主たち！
The boys after the reward.
しつこいね！ とどめを刺しに来たのかい!? この小僧共！
You again! Have you come to kill me,
you little brats!
森で聞いた声！いた！
That voice, in the forest. It's her!
あにき、この女がクモのバケモンだ
This woman is the spider monster.
やっぱりそいつが人さらいだ！
I knew she was the kidnapper!
いっちゃん、そいつから離れな 干からびちまうぜ？
Get away from her, old man.
She'll suck you dry.
バケモンをやっつければメシが食える
We can get food if we beat the monster.
サクッと頼むぜあにき！
Go get her, Hyakkimaru.
おはぎがバケモン？
Ohagi, a monster?
おいらの言うことがわっかんねぇのかよ！
Don't you get what I'm saying?
その女はバケモンで人さらいなんだって！
That woman is a monster and a kidnapper!
人さらいはこの俺だ
I'm the kidnapper.
俺が手引きしてこの村から逃がした
I've helped people escape from here.
おはぎは関係ない
Ohagi didn't do it.
俺は捕まってもいいが、おはぎは見逃してくれ！
I don't mind being caught,
but please let Ohagi go.
病にかかって弱っているんだ！
She's sick and weakened.
病って…なんでバケモンをかばうんだよ
Sick? Why protect a monster!
貴様が逃がし屋か！手間取らせやがって
So you're the one behind it all.
We finally got you.
見つけたのはおいらたちだぜ？褒美はもらえるんだろうな！
We're the ones that found him.
We can have that reward, right?
そんなものないわ！密告者を釣るための方便よ！
Yeah, right. We just said that
to lure any squealers.
そんな殺生な！
That's too cruel.
やり方が汚ぇぜ！お前らは悪党だ！
That's dirty, you guys are villains!
悪党結構！
Fine with us.
これ以上人足に足退けされて上がりが減ったら、 俺たちが始末されちまう
If we lose any more workers and
work slows down, our heads will go flying.
その男を捕らえろ！
Catch that man!
まずい精気だねぇ
Tastes disgusting.
あにき…
Bro...
見逃しちゃもらえないようだね
I see you won't let me go.
何ボーっとしてんだい！ あんたの仕事は終わってないよ逃がし屋！ どっちに行けばいいんだい
Don't just stand there.
Your job isn't done yet. Which way?
あっちだ！
-That way!
-Okay.
よし！
あにき、ちょっとじっとしてて
Hyakkimaru, stay still for a bit.
色々アテが外れてタダ働きになっちゃうけど  どうする？
I was wrong about the reward,
so what now?
付き合うぜあにき！
I'm with ya!
何だい怖いのかい？ こうでもしなきゃ追いつかれるよ
What, you're scared?
They'll catch up to us if we walk.
大丈夫だ！
I'm fine.
じゃあ一気にいくよ！
Then here we go.
そらっ！
Ready?
もう…すっかり…元気だな…！
You're all in good health now, it seems.
もう俺がいなくても、どこへでも行けるだろう
You won't need me anymore, huh.
まだ山を越えられるほど力は戻ってないよ
I'm not strong enough
to cross the mountain.
あと5、6人は男の精気を吸わないとね
I need to suck out
5 or 6 more men's life force.
人を…殺すのか？
Do you kill them?
人間は貴重なエサだからね 今まで命まで取ったことはないよ
Humans are precious prey.
I don't take their lives.
生きてりゃ人間の精気は戻る
If they're alive,
their life force revives.
そいつをまた吸うんだ  共に生きるのが長生きの秘訣…
Then I suck it out again. Living together
is the secret to a long life.
そうか…これからも か…
I see. From now on too, right?
Yeah.
ならいい
Good.
あにきー！
Hyakkimaru!
いくらあにきでもここは登れねぇだろ
Not even you could climb this.
あいつらの後を追うしかねぇよ  行こうぜ
We'll just have to go after them.
Let's go.
これが抜け道なのかい？
This is the secret passage?
入り口は狭いが、奥は広くなってる
It's small here, but wider inside.
水音が聞こえるだろ？
Hear that water?
水の流れに沿って行けば、山の裏の沢に出られる
Follow it and you'll reach the stream
on the other side.
天然の洞窟だ
It's a natural cave.
お前なら灯りはいらないし、 追いつかれることもないだろう
You won't need a light.
They'll never catch you.
俺の仕事はここまでだ さぁ、行ってくれ
My job is done. Now go.
あんたも行くんだよ」
You're coming, too.
裏の仕事がバレちまったんだから、 もうここにはいられないだろ？
You can't stay here now that
they know your identity.
捕まってタダで済むと思ってんのかい？
Think of what they'll do to you.
見せしめにされるのは間違いないだろうな…
Yes, they'll use me to warn people.
それで本望なのかい？
Is that what you want?
いや…
-No...
-Then let's escape.
なら逃げるしかないだろう
バケモンと一緒じゃイヤかい？
Don't want to be with a monster?
おはぎ…わかった！
Okay, Ohagi.
この村で死ぬくらいなら、 ここから逃れてお前のエサとして生きていくか
Instead of dying here in this village,
I'll live on as your prey.
あんたみたいなおかしな人間にゃ、 今後二度と出会えないだろうよ
I'll never meet a human
as strange as you again.
じゃあ早速…
Then let's go...
あんた！
No!
領主様に楯突いたやつの末路だ
That's what happens
when you betray the lord.
化け物女とともにトドメを刺せ！
Kill him together with the monster woman!
貴様ら！
You bastards!
1人残らず吸い尽くしてやる！
I'll drain every drop
of your life force!
あにき！
Hyakkimaru!
この村に医者はいないんだろう？
There's no doctor here, right?
私がお前を連れて行く
Then I will take you to one.
お前を死なせはしないよ…
I won't let you die.
やっぱりどっちかが死ななきゃならないようだねぇ…
I see one of us will have to die.
殺すのは…ダメだ…
No, don't kill...
おはぎ、今までも… これからも、だろ…？
Ohagi, you never have,
and you never will, right?
行っちまったなぁ… あの2人
They're gone now.
人と仲良くなるあやかしもいるなんて
A ghoul that likes a human, huh.
世の中わかんねぇもんだなぁ！
The world's full of surprises.
でもさ、あにきの耳が戻っててよかったよな
But it's a good thing
your hearing was back.
じゃなきゃかなーり後味の悪い結果になってたと思うぜ？
Or else it would've ended
in a really awkward way.
まだ喋る気になんないのか…
Still don't want to speak?
ならいいよ！おいらが2人ぶん喋りまくって ジメジメ気分を晴らしてやるさ！
Fine, I'll talk enough for two
and cheer things up.
わっ！クモ！いってぇ…
Huh? A spider, ouch!
こいつ噛みやがった！
It bit me!
ごめんよ…驚かしちまったのはおいらだな…
Sorry, I'm the one that scared you, huh.
え？あにき、今…
Hey, did you just...
鼻で笑ったろ！
You laughed at me!
聞こえたぜあにきの最初の笑い声！
I heard that, your first laugh!
でも違うんだよ！おいらの求めてる笑いは！
But that's not the kind I wanted to hear.
そんな人を小馬鹿にしたようなんじゃなくて！
Not the kind that makes fun of people.
A happier laugh, you know?
憂鬱が風に散らばり
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
吹き溜まって影になる
piling up to form shadows
僕らの足音は　無用を饒舌に諭す
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
君の瞳の深さを覗き見て狼狽える
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
望みなどあったでしょうか　この行き先には
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
戯けて笑うのは
I feign amusement and laugh
この道が暗いから
because this road is so dark
灯りを灯すのに　僕がいるでしょう
I will be there to shine the light
さよならごっこは慣れたもんさ
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
でも手を振ったら泣いちゃった
but I cried when I waved to you
僕らの真っ赤な悲しみが 暮れる 暮れる そして夜が来る
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
当たり前にやってくる明日なら
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
生きたいなんて言わなかった
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
よせばいいのに夢見てしまう 未来 未来 君のせいなんだ
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame
"Jorogumo"